# Md Shakil Ahmed

□ +880 130 846 6291 | ② ahmedmshakil1@gmail.com | 🖬 LinkedIn | ۞ GitHub | ۞ Portfolio | ۞ Dhaka, Bangladesh

#### Summary

A Computer Science and Engineering student from Independent University, Bangladesh who is Self-motivated, highly passionate for the technology and possesses a strong interest in researching data science, Natural language processing and machine learning in the hopes of making a substantial impact on the field.

## RESEARCH INTERESTS

Data Science, Machine Learning, Natural Language Processing, Image Processing, Bioinformatics, Blockchain, Software Engineering, System Design

#### EDUCATION

## Independent University, Bangladesh

B.Sc. in Computer Science and Engineering;

Thesis: credit risk rating system using Blockchain

Dhaka, Bangladesh January 2021 – December 2024

Ongoing

• Relevant coursework: Calculus I-II, Differential Equations, Digital System Design, Data Structure, Algorithms, Object Oriented Programming, Database Management System, Distributed Database System

#### WORK EXPERIENCE

## Independent University, Bangladesh

Bashundhara R/A, Dhaka, Bangladesh

Undergraduate Teaching Assistant

Jan 2023 – Sep 2023

• Courses Taught: Structured Programming (Programming language: Python), Database Management.

#### Klatch Technologies

Assam, India (Remote)

AI Research and Development Intern

Oct 2023 - Dec 2023

- Implemented common NLP tasks using transformers such as named-entity recognition (NER), part-of-speech (POS) tagging, sentiment analysis, text classification, and extractive/generative question answering.
- Intent-based Query Model for Question Answering
- Worked on a custom Medical domain question-answering system by fine-tuning a BERT base model transformer. Evaluated the exact match and F1 scores using different Medical data sets and compared the evaluation results.

#### Student Tutor

Uttara, Dhaka, Bangladesh (Part-time)

Teacher

 $Feb \ 2020-present$ 

- Work with students, and indoctrinate them about problems they are having with the course material.
- Holding 15 hours per week's tution hours.
- Lead discussion sessions with students.

#### RESEARCH EXPERIENCE

## Research On going

# AWARDS & ACHIEVEMENTS

Ahsanullah Master Smriti Scholarship: Awarded to the 9th and 17th place twice (2008, 2009) for outstanding performance among Gazipur District at Primary Level Scholarship Exam.

Best Athelate Award: Awarded to the Champion price twice (2014, 2016) for securing three 1st place in the Annual sports competition in UHSC

## Projects

## Invoice Generator Using Python | GitHub

• In this project, I create a real time invoice generator using python to generate automated shopping invoice.

## Student Performance Monitoring System 2.0 for IUB | GitHub

• This is the database management project that we implement graphs and charts for the all users those who using iras.

#### Hotel Management System Covid-19 | GitHub

- Real-time Employee management system object and Face Recognition using RCNN, Redis Docker, Django
- Manage category of room, Health care, and payment. Based on the customer's situation suggest a hospital

## SKILLS

**Programming:** C++, Java, Python, JavaScript, MATLAB, SQL, MySQL

Technologies: Git, Github, Gitlab, GitKraken, OpenCV

Languages: Bangla (Native), English (Professional), French (Elementary)

## Competitive Programming

**Problem-Solving:** Solved numerous data structure and algorithmic problems and participated in online programming contests in various online judges including Codeforces, Codechef and Atcoder.